Priyanka Murugan

(415) 818 - 7619 ♦ pkrmu@ucdavis.edu ♦ San Francisco, CA ♦ LinkedIn ♦ GitHub

PROFILE

Analytics professional with two years of full-time experience working in Marketing Analytics with outstanding stakeholder relationship management skills

Domains: Exploratory Data Analysis, Experimental Design and Analysis, A/B Testing

Languages: Python, R, SQL (MySQL, BigQuery)

Technologies: Tableau, GCP, Gurobi, MongoDB, Git, Alteryx (ETL), Advanced Excel, Flask, Snowflake

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

American Eagle Outfitters (AEO)

San Francisco, CA

Summary: As part of the MSBA Practicum, optimized supply chain for an international fashion retailer, with annual revenue of \$3.7B

Business Analyst [Sep. 2022 –]

- Utilized Gurobi to perform linear programming to improve current Optimization Model
- Created Tableau Dashboard to visualize store-to-store transfers

Novartis Healthcare Pvt. Ltd.

Hyderabad, India

Summary: An industry leader in delivering personalized experience to doctors via omnichannel marketing engagement.

Awards & Achievements: Star Impact Award for Individuals for three consecutive quarters
Business Analyst, Marketing Analytics

[Sep. 2021 – Jun. 2022]

- Experimental analysis: Conducted A/B tests to measure the impact of touchpoint recommendations on the KPIs over months observing an overall **6% improvement** in treatment group
- Utilized SHAP framework to analyze the impact of predicted touchpoint sequences on maximizing sales
- Physician Segmentation: Implemented K-means clustering to identify 16 unique physician personas based on behavioral features
- Attribution Model: Implemented a log-linear regression model with 95% pseudo R-squared in order to predict prescription sales made by doctors
- Operationalized end-to-end pipeline catering to data pre-processing and EDA using Python

Associate Analyst, Marketing Analytics

[Aug.2020 – Aug. 2021]

- Implemented targeting strategy of physicians for various oncology products using Alteryx and SQL achieving 30% increase in digital channel utilization by sales reps in Q3 2021
- Built an ETL data pipeline in Alteryx to ingest multiple data sources of 100M+ rows to generate weekly reports, reducing processing time from multiple hours to 30 minutes per day
- Organized 3+ sponsored site-wide quizzing events with a reach of 1000+ associates as part of Quizzards,
 Novartis

PROJECTS

• **US News Scrapper and Sentiment Analyzer** – Built a web scrapper using BeautifulSoup to extract U.S. News Headlines and perform sentiment analysis. Project is deployed as a <u>Streamlit Application</u>

EDUCATION

University of California, Davis

San Francisco, CA

Master of Science, Business Analytics

[Aug.2022 - Jun. 2023]

Highlighted Coursework: Data Management, Advanced Statistics, Big Data, Cloud Computing, Machine Learning Awards & Achievements: GSM Grant (\$7,000 scholarship), MSBA Fellowship (\$9,500 scholarship)

Visvesvaraya National Institute of Technology, Nagpur

Nagpur, India

Bachelor of Technology, Metallurgical and Materials Engineering, (3.1/4.0)

[Jul. 2016 – Jul. 2020]

Highlighted Coursework: Computer Programming, Calculus, Linear Algebra

Awards & Achievements: Co-authored a research paper in Materials Today: Proceedings journal (2021) [Link], Won Gold at All India Inter-NIT Lawn Tennis Meet (2018)